Guide to the Berkeley Divinity School Records
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Academics School Life, Series VI
  - Academic Programs
    - Field Education
      - Field Education Supervisors, 1980-1981 (Box 65, Folder 208-209)
      - Social Organization Supervisors Coordinator, 1981 (Box 65, Folder 210)
      - Field Education Staff, 1983-1984 (Box 65, Folder 211)
      - Field Education Shelter Proposal, 1979-1980 (Box 65, Folder 212)
      - Field Education Traineeships, 1974-1981 (Box 65, Folder 213)
      - Workstudy Placements, 1980-1981 (Box 65, Folder 214)
      - Waterbury Area Episcopal Council, 1971 (Box 65, Folder 215)
      - West Haven Adult Day Center, 1980 (Box 65, Folder 216)
      - Internship Sites
        - Ansonia, Christ Church - North Haven, St. John's, 1984-1993 (Box 65, Folder 225-275)
        - Newington, Grace - Woodbury, St. Paul's, 1984-1993 (Box 66, Folder 276-314, 320)
    - Placements
      - Placements and Planning, 1974-1984 (Box 65, Folder 217-219)
      - Internships, 1975-1982 (Box 65, Folder 220)
      - Episcopal Field Placements, 1976-1991 (Box 65, Folder 221-224)
      - Student Placements, 1986-1991 (Box 66, Folder 315-319)
    - General Ordination Exams (GOEs)
      - Correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box 66, Folder 321)
      - General Board of Examining Chaplains, 1985-1986 (Box 66, Folder 322)
      - GOE, 1972-1991 (Box 66, Folder 323-341)
    - Core Groups
      - Core Group Program Information, 1972-1976 (Box 67, Folder 342-343)
      - Core Group Planning, 1971-1976 (Box 67, Folder 344-349)
      - Core Group Evaluations, 1971-1973 (Box 67, Folder 350-352)
      - Core Group Report to Faculty, 1975-1976 (Box 67, Folder 353)
      - Core Group Application Forms, 1974-1976 (Box 67, Folder 354)
      - Core Group Tutors, 1972-1974 (Box 67, Folder 355-356)
      - Hospital Core Group, 1972-1977 (Box 67, Folder 357-360)
      - Parish Core Group, 1972-1974 (Box 67, Folder 361-367)
      - Urban Ministry Core Group Evaluations, 1974-1975 (Box 67, Folder 368)
      - Westport Cluster, 1972 (Box 67, Folder 369)
  - Events
    - Commencement
      - Commencement, 1966-1981 (Box 67, Folder 370-376)
      - Commencement, 1925-1965 (Box 68, Folder 377-384)
      - Commencement addresses (Box 68, Folder 385)
    - Convocation
      - Sample brochures, 1986-1992 (Box 68, Folder 386)
      - Convocation Worship, 1992 (Box 68, Folder 389)
      - Convocations (Box 68, Folder 391-404)
      - Convocations, 1972-1988 (Box 69, Folder 405-423)
      - Convocation, 1964 (Box 69, Folder 423-424)
      - Convocation - 100th Anniversary, 1954 (Box 69, Folder 425)
    - Lectures
      - Lectures Addresses, 1960-1982 (Box 69, Folder 426-427)
      - Cheney Lectures, 1978-1992 (Box 68, Folder 387, 388, 390, 395)
      - Mark Gibbs Lecture, 1981 (Box 69, Folder 128)
      - William Lyon Phelps Lecture (Box 69, Folder 429)
      - Peter Ainslie Lecture on Christian Unity, 1986 (Box 69, Folder 430)
      - Mary Fitch Page Lectures, 1935-1968 (Box 69, Folder 431-436)
      - Kingsbury Lectures, 1948-1969 (Box 70, Folder 437-439)
      - Kittel Lecture, 1991 (Box 68, Folder 394)
      - Louis W. Pitt Lecture, 1991 (Box 68, Folder 396)
      - Louis W. Pitt Lectures, 1961-1986 (Box 70, Folder 440-442)
    - Other events
      - Emerging Muslim-Christian Encounters: YDS-BDS Seminar, 1999 (Box 70, Folder 443)
      - YDS-BDS Seminar brochures, 1998-1999 (Box 70, Folder 744)
      - Ethics Forum, 1998 (Box 70, Folder 445)
      - Seeking Peace in the Culture Wars: YDS-BDS Seminar, 1997 (Box 70, Folder 446)
      - Large Parish Conference, 1996-2001 (Box 70, Folder 447)
      - YDS-BDS Seminar brochures, 1995-1996 (Box 70, Folder 448)
      - Ethics Forum, 1995-1996 (Box 70, Folder 449)
      - re-Advent Retreat for Clergy and Lay Ministers, 1995 (Box 70, Folder 450)
      - The Institute for Professional Competencies in the Practice of Ministry, 1993-1994 (Box 70, Folder 451)
      - BDS/YDS Merger 20th Anniversary, 1991 (Box 70, Folder 452)
      - Yale Strike, 1985 (Box 70, Folder 453)
      - Hymnal 1982 Workshop, 1984 (Box 70, Folder 454)
      - International Human Rights Law Project, 1982 (Box 70, Folder 455)
      - Conference on Evangelism (Box 70, Folder 456)
      - Mexico City Mission Trip, 1982 (Box 70, Folder 457)
      - BDS/YDS Merger 10th Anniversary, 1981 (Box 70, Folder 458)
      - South African Visit, 1980-1981 (Box 70, Folder 459)
      - Colloquium on Family and the Christian Church, 1978-1979 (Box 70, Folder 460)
      - The Future of Education Ministry Forum, 1977-1978 (Box 70, Folder 461-462)
      - The Berkeley Series, 1975 (Box 70, Folder 463)
      - Opening of the Berkeley Center, 1971 (Box 70, Folder 464)
      - The Coburn Statement (Seminarians and the Draft), 1968 (Box 70, Folder 465)
      - Opening Addresses, 1957-1968 (Box 70, Folder 466)
      - Founders Day Celebrations, 1954-1969 (Box 70, Folder 467)
  - Arts and Media
    - Art Exhibits, 1973-1982 (Box 70, Folder 468-471)
    - Art Exhibits, 1971-1973 (Box 71, Folder 472-473)
    - Television: Barbara Stetson "Education for Ministry: Berkeley Divnity School at Yale", 1980-1982 (Box 71, Folder 474)
    - Television: NBC Special "Some Kind of Presence", 1971-1972 (Box 71, Folder 475)
    - Television: 8th Day, 1971-1972 (Box 71, Folder 476)
    - Communications, 1972-1975 (Box 71, Folder 477)
  - Library
    - Correspondence, 1970-1982 (Box 71, Folder 478-480)
    - BDS Library Appraisal, 1971 (Box 71, Folder 481)
    - Special Collections: Harry Knox Sherrill Papers, 1981 (Box 71, Folder 482)
    - Paul Vieth Christian Education Service, 1977-1987 (Box 71, Folder 483)
    - Visual Education Service, 1978-1980 (Box 71, Folder 484)
  - Student Life
    - Worship
      - St. Luke's Committee, 1974-1997 (Box 71, Folder 485-490)
      - YDS Worship Committee, 1974-1981 (Box 71, Folder 491-492)
      - Berkeley Worship Committee, 1965-1972 (Box 71, Folder 493-494)
      - St. Luke's Customary, 1984-1985 (Box 71, Folder 495)
      - Celebrant Ceremonial Guides, 1967-1969 (Box 71, Folder 496)
      - Sacristan Notes, 1984, 1997 (Box 71, Folder 497-498)
      - Chapel Services and Schedules, 1970-1971 (Box 71, Folder 499)
      - Dedication of St. Luke's Chapel, 1983 (Box 71, Folder 500)
      - Services, 1976-1987 (Box 71, Folder 501)
      - St. Luke's Chapel Services, 1960-1970 (Box 71, Folder 502)
      - Services, 1949-1976 (Box 71, Folder 503)
      - Special Services, 1949-1968 (Box 71, Folder 504)
      - Dedication of Buildings, 1928 (Box 71, Folder 505)
      - Wednesday Evening Services, 1981-1982 (Box 71, Folder 506)
      - Marquand Worship, 1971-1982 (Box 72, Folder 507)
      - BDS Service Music Booklet, 1958 (Box 72, Folder 508)
      - Alumni Installations, 1948-1969 (Box 72, Folder 509)
      - Berkeley School Prayers (Box 72, Folder 510)
      - Seabury Altar, Chalice, and Paten, 1930-1971 (Box 72, Folder 511-513)
    - Student Groups
      - Berkeley Student Associaton, 1962-1970 (Box 72, Folder 514-515)
      - Yale Black Seminarians, 1972-1978 (Box 72, Folder 516)
      - Center for Human Rights, 1982 (Box 72, Folder 517)
      - Glocal Community Association, 1981-1983 (Box 72, Folder 518)
      - International Forum, 1977 (Box 72, Folder 519)
      - Liturgical League, 1940 (Box 72, Folder 520)
      - Missionary Society, 1965 (Box 72, Folder 521)
      - Prayer Groups, 1977 (Box 72, Folder 522)
      - Theological Students Fellowship, 1984 (Box 72, Folder 523)
      - Wives Association, no date (Box 72, Folder 524)
      - Women's Center, 1975-1985 (Box 72, Folder 525-526)
      - Women's Team Ministry, 1973 (Box 72, Folder 527)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Miscellaneous papers (Box 72, Folder 528-529)
    - Correspondence, 1928-1978 (Box 72, Folder 530)
    - Letters from Bishops (autographs), 1911-1942 (Box 72, Folder 531)
    - Church Pension Fund, 1985-1986 (Box 72, Folder 532-533)
    - Church Life Insurance, 1984-1985 (Box 72, Folder 534)
    - Health Care / Insurance, 1940-1981 (Box 72, Folder 535)
    - Almy and Son Inc., 1980-1991 (Box 72, Folder 536)
    - Berkeley Cross, 1984 (Box 72, Folder 537)
    - Berkeley Bookstore, 1950-1969 (Box 72, Folder 538)
    - Psychiatrists, 1984 (Box 72, Folder 539)
    - Yale Reports, 1973 (Box 72, Folder 540)
    - Cultural Committee on Relations with Poland, 1974-1975 (Box 72, Folder 541)
    - School Visitors, 1970-1980 (Box 72, Folder 542-543)
- History, Series VII
  - YDS/BDS Merger
    - YDS/BDS Agreement, 1985 (Box 72, Folder 544)
    - YDS/BDS Affiliation Documents, 1984 (Box 72, Folder 545)
    - The Mission of Berkeley at Yale, 1982-1984 (Box 72, Folder 546)
    - Berkeley/Yale Affiliation, 1976 (Box 72, Folder 547)
    - YDS-BDS Agreements, 1970-1975 (Box 72, Folder 548-552)
  - Formation of Berkeley
    - School Name, 1971 (Box 72, Folder 553)
    - School Seal, no date (Box 72, Folder 554)
    - School Motto, no date (Box 72, Folder 555)
    - School Milestones, 1969-1983 (Box 72, Folder 556)
    - Stationery, 1975 (Box 72, Folder 557)
    - Mission Statements, 1982-1987 (Box 72, Folder 558)
    - Potential Merger Opportunities, 1970-1980 (Box 72, Folder 559)
    - 100th Anniversary, 1954 (Box 72, Folder 560)
    - Correspondence of E.B. Raftery (historian), 1931-1972 (Box 72, Folder 561)
    - Bishop Berkeley Celebration, 1928 (Box 73, Folder 1)
    - Bishop Berkeley, 1920-1929 (Box 73, Folder 2)
    - The Founding of Berkeley, 1855 (Box 73, Folder 3)
  - Chronological History
    - BDS history, 1881-1990 (Box 73, Folder 4-8)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Ted Ferris' Sermons, 1983 (Box 73, Folder 9)
    - Barmen Declaration, 1973 (Box 73, Folder 10)
    - Memorabilia (Box 73, Folder 11)
    - Berkeleyana, 1905-1984 (Box 73, Folder 12-18)
    - Deceased American Bishops, 1800s-1930 (Box 73, Folder 19-25)
- Publications, Series VIII
  - Catalogues and Bulletins
    - Catalogues, 1857-1912 (Box 75, Folder 47-57)
    - Catalogues, 1945-1971 (Box 75, Folder 31-47)
    - Catalogue Revisions, 1971-1991 (Box 75, Folder 30)
    - Quarterly Bulletin, 1909-1934 (Box 77, Folder 112-120)
    - Quarterly Bulletin, 1940-1968 (Box 76, Folder 85-111)
  - Newsletters
    - Divinity Dial, 1974-1983 (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - Newsletter - Dean Annand, 1983-1986 (Box 74, Folder 2-5)
    - Newsletter - Dean Clark, 1978-1981 (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - Memos to Faculty and Students, 1972-1982 (Box 74, Folder 7)
    - Building Churches, 1972-1973 (Box 74, Folder 22)
    - Berkeley Newsletter, 1997-2002 (Box 74, Folder 25-26)
    - Berkeley Serves, 1975-1985 (Box 75, Folder 60)
    - Emanon, 1966-1969 (Box 75, Folder 62-63)
    - Group Relations Publications, 1977 (Box 75, Folder 64)
    - Prospector, 1955-1970 (Box 75, Folder 65-68)
    - Ultra, 1987 (Box 76, Folder 71)
  - Liturgical Publications
    - Lenten Meditations, 1982-1984 (Box 76, Folder 72)
    - Eucharistic Celebrations, 1968 (Box 76, Folder 73)
  - Letters
    - Berkeley Buzz, 2000 (Box 74, Folder 8)
    - Letters to Entering Students, 1978-1984 (Box 74, Folder 9)
    - Communications, 1973-1974 (Box 74, Folder 10)
  - Alumni
    - Directories, 2001-2002 (Box 75, Folder 29)
    - Alumni Notices, 1969-1974 (Box 74, Folder 11-15)
    - Alumni Notices, 1963-1970 (Box 75, Folder 58-59)
    - Alumni Notices and Writings, 1960-2003 (Box 77, Folder 127-133)
    - Easter Cards, 1967-1970 (Box 76, Folder 74)
    - Christmas Cards, 1944-1970 (Box 76, Folder 75)
  - About Berkeley
    - Literature about Berkeley, 1943-1961 (Box 76, Folder 83)
    - Literature about Berkeley, 1951-1974 (Box 74, Folder 16-18)
    - Literature about Berkeley, 1966-1995 (Box 76, Folder 76-81)
    - Literature about Berkeley, 2000s (Box 75, Folder 27)
    - The Forward Look, 1959 (Box 76, Folder 82)
    - Berkeley Viewbooks, no date (Box 76, Folder 84)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Newspaper Articles, 1910-1990 (Box 77, Folder 121-126)
    - Berkeley Friends Mailing Lists, 1968, 1986 (Box 74, Folder 19)
    - Brochures, new releases, printed material, 1950-2002 (Box 74, Folder 134-136, Box 75, Folder 20-24, Box 77, Folder 28)
- Related Organizations, Series IX
  - Diocese of Connecticut
    - Bicentennial, 1983-1984 (Box 77, Folder 137)
    - Diocese of CT, 1971-1982 (Box 77, Folder 138-139)
    - Diocese of CT, 1975-1984 (Box 78, Folder 40)
    - The Rt. Rev. Clarence N. Coleridge, 1981-1983 (Box 77, Folder 140)
    - The Rt. Rev. Arthur E. Walmsley, 1979-1984 (Box 77, Folder 141)
    - The Rev. Douglas T. Cooke, 1979-1982 (Box 77, Folder 142)
    - The Rt. Rev. Morgan Porteus, 1975-1981 (Box 77, Folder 143)
    - Altar Guild, 1978-1985 (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Deacons' Program, 1973-1974 (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - Ecumenical Worship, 1981 (Box 78, Folder 3)
    - Ecumenical Commission, 1979-1982 (Box 78, Folder 4)
    - Episcopal Church Women, 1978-1985 (Box 78, Folder 5)
    - Episcopal Social Service, 1971-1981 (Box 78, Folder 6)
    - Hispanic Ministry, 1982 (Box 78, Folder 7)
    - Instituto Pastoral Hispano, 1977-1982 (Box 78, Folder 8)
    - Venture in Mission, 1977-1981 (Box 78, Folder 9-11, 22)
  - Council of Deans
    - Council of Deans, 1977-1986 (Box 78, Folder 12-2-)
    - By-Laws, 1977 (Box 78, Folder 23)
  - Episcopal Church Center
    - Episcopal Church Center, 1974-1985 (Box 78, Folder 24-26, 41)
    - Hispanic Ministry, 1983-1986 (Box 78, Folder 27)
    - Presiding Bishop's Fund for World Relief, 1981-1982 (Box 78, Folder 28)
    - Mission Education Task Force, 1981 (Box 78, Folder 29)
    - Stewardship Committee, 1981 (Box 78, Folder 30)
    - Volunteers in Mission, 1979-1982 (Box 78, Folder 31)
    - Evangelism and Renewal, 1979-1980 (Box 78, Folder 32)
    - Overseas Leadership Development Program, 1978-1983 (Box 78, Folder 33)
    - Commission for Black Ministry, 1974-1983 (Box 78, Folder 34)
  - The Episcopal Church
    - Bishops
      - Bishop Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 78, Folder 35)
      - Bishop Correspondence, 1970-1972 (Box 78, Folder 36)
      - Bishop M.A. DeWolfe Howe, 1895 (Box 79, Folder 64)
      - Bishop signatures, 1937 (Box 79, Folder 84-85)
    - Dioceses
      - Dioceses of Ohio, Washington, Western Mass., Central Florida, Iowa, Massachusetts, Rhode Island, Newark, 1977-1986 (Box 78, Folder 37-46)
      - Diocese of Buffalo, 1985 (Box 79, Folder 63)
    - General Convention
      - General Conventon, 1973, 1979, 1983 (Box 78, Folder 47-49)
      - House of Bishops, 1972-1984 (Box 79, Folder 50)
      - General Convention, 1970 (Box 79, Folder 51)
      - Prayer Book Revision, 1970-1976 (Box 79, Folder 52)
    - Ministries
      - Council for the Development of Ministry, 1985 (Box 79, Folder 53)
      - Evangelical Education Society, 1984 (Box 79, Folder 54)
      - Episcopal Radio and Television Foundation, 1981-1982 (Box 79, Folder 55)
      - Black Ministries, 1979, 1981 (Box 79, Folder 56-57)
      - Evangelical Education Society, 1978-1981 (Box 79, Folder 58)
      - Ministry to the Aging, 1975-1985 (Box 79, Folder 59)
      - Commission on Ministry, 1975-1976 (Box 79, Folder 60)
      - Episcopal Church Women, 1974-1984 (Box 79, Folder 61)
      - Episcopal Church Annual, 1971-1985 (Box 79, Folder 62)
      - Episcopal Camp Conference Center, 1973-1974 (Box 80, Folder 115)
      - Episcopal Church at Yale, 1971-1976 (Box 80, Folder 117)
      - Episcopal Consortium for Theological Education in the Northeast, 1971-1980 (Box 80, Folder 118)
      - Episcopal Social Services, 1982-1986 (Box 80, Folder 119)
  - Other Seminaries
    - Seminaries-Development Officers, 1982 (Box 79, Folder 65)
    - Hartford Seminary Foundation, 1977-1978 (Box 79, Folder 66)
    - Nashotah House, 1977-1985 (Box 79, Folder 67)
    - Seabury Western, 1977-1981 (Box 78, Folder 21)
    - Sewanee, 1953-1986 (Box 79, Folder 68)
    - Virginia Theological Seminary, 1978-1986 (Box 79, Folder 69)
  - Association of Theological Schools (ATS)
    - ATS Workshop, 1981 (Box 79, Folder 70)
    - ATS, 1975-1986 (Box 79, Folder 71)
    - Biennial Meeting, 1972 (Box 79, Folder 72)
    - American ATS, 1957-1984 (Box 79, Folder 73-76)
  - Board for Theological Education (BTE)
    - Board for Theological Education (BTE), 1968-1986 (Box 79, Folder 77-83)
  - Churches
    - St. Andrew's - New Haven, 1981 (Box 79, Folder 86)
    - St. David's - Gales Ferry, 1974-1982 (Box 79, Folder 87)
    - St. George's House - England, 1977 (Box 79, Folder 88)
    - St. John's - Bridgeport, 1981 (Box 79, Folder 89)
    - St. John's - New Haven, 1979 (Box 79, Folder 90)
    - Kent School - Kent, 1979-1981 (Box 79, Folder 91)
    - St. Luke's - Darien, 1983 (Box 79, Folder 92)
    - St. Luke's - New Haven, 1981 (Box 79, Folder 93)
    - St. Mary's Priory - New Haven, 1986 (Box 79, Folder 94)
    - St. Paul's - New Haven, 1975-1984 (Box 79, Folder 95)
  - Episcopal Church Foundation (ECF)
    - Correspondence, 1971-1988 (Box 80, Folder 96)
    - Fellowships, 1990-1991 (Box 80, Folder 97)
    - Fellows, 1972-1985 (Box 80, Folder 98)
    - LA Advisory Council, 1982 (Box 80, Folder 99)
  - Other Organizations
    - Absalom Jones Theological Institute, 1971-1978 (Box 80, Folder 100)
    - Arts National Endowment, 1974 (Box 80, Folder 101)
    - Alban Institute, 1975-1982 (Box 80, Folder 102)
    - Anglican Theological Review, 1972-1985 (Box 80, Folder 103)
    - APPA Conference, 1991 (Box 80, Folder 104)
    - Anglican-Roman Catholic International Commission, 1979 (Box 80, Folder 105)
    - Association for Case Training, 1979-1981 (Box 80, Folder 106)
    - Association for Theological Field Education, 1976-1981 (Box 80, Folder 107)
    - Association Parishes, 1974-1980 (Box 80, Folder 108)
    - Black Episcopal Seminarians, 1972-1983 (Box 80, Folder 109)
    - Board of Ordained Ministry, 1981 (Box 80, Folder 110)
    - The Clergy Journal, 1983 (Box 80, Folder 111)
    - College of Preachers, 1977-1986 (Box 80, Folder 112)
    - Council for Religion in Independent School, 1972-1978 (Box 80, Folder 113)
    - Cowley Fathers, 1980 (Box 80, Folder 114)
    - Evangelical Education Society, 1984 (Box 80, Folder 120)
    - Fund for Theological Education, 1977-1982 (Box 80, Folder 121)
    - Global Solidarity in Theological Education, 1981 (Box 80, Folder 122)
    - Holy Cross Monastery, 1979-1982 (Box 80, Folder 123)
    - Hospice, 1975 (Box 80, Folder 124)
    - Human Relations Institute, 1978 (Box 80, Folder 125)
    - lntegrity, 1974-1979 (Box 80, Folder 126)
    - Inter-Seminary Newsletter, 1972-1978 (Box 80, Folder 127)
    - ISTEM, 1979 (Box 80, Folder 128)
    - Killam's Point, 1985 (Box 80, Folder 129)
    - Lay School of Religion, 1978-1982 (Box 80, Folder 130)
    - The Living Church, 1979-1986 (Box 80, Folder 131)
    - Mutual Ministry, 1978 (Box 80, Folder 132)
    - National Association of Retired Persons, 1976-1977 (Box 80, Folder 133)
    - New England Parish Training Program, 1975-1980 (Box 80, Folder 134)
    - New Haven Deanery, 1977-1981 (Box 80, Folder 135)
    - New Haven Memorial Society, 1980 (Box 80, Folder 136)
    - Overseas Ministries Study Center, 1976-1983 (Box 80, Folder 137)
    - Renewal of Mission Conference, 1977 (Box 80, Folder 138)
    - St. Raphael's Hospital, 1975-1979 (Box 80, Folder 139)